Now, let's see the deck implementation in sea.
We have seen that ad different method and add real methods, and we have talked about that, about these
methods and how they work in their previous videos.
So please go back to see how to add the from and how to add the rear methods.
And we have said that the main key here is to ensure that the pointer at the front and the point that
trigger is added correctly and moved correctly.
And the last step is assigning the array at the front in case we are adding at the front equal to the
item and array at index three equal to item.
If we are adding at the rear, there is another method called delete front.
It starts by taking in a V and end from front and rear integer as per meter and into item.
If front equality from minus one, then the deck is empty.
Then we assign the item equal to array at the front and the array at front equal to zero.
And we start checking if the front equal to the rear, then front, equal, rear, equal minus one.
I start by and re enclosing them at the minus one and L's front plus plus increase front by one and
then return the it.
If we want to delete that, here is also it took RIAA the front end every year in the same way we are
checking if the front is equally minus one, always use the front to check if the queue is is empty
or not.
Then Item Equal Array, but here is an index editor is and it is not at index front.
OK, so the lead from the front we use array at front and delete delete from rear equal array at rear
array, a rear equal equal to zero, then rear minus one.
And if rear equal minus one than the front equal to minus one, assign them to minus one returned height.
OK.
This these are the methods they lead from and delete the deleting the elements at the front and rear,
respectively.
This play, this method took that array.
And by the way, just for remembering you when using the cue, we are dealing with editors, so we are
passing an array here and avoid this play.
Print at the front, we use the loo in order to assign the values here and start printing them at index.
So a rate at the next I printed correctly.
Now we need to make a new method called Int Count.
It took in two separate meter array and we have C equal to zero and die.
We start making a loop to count the array elements.
We have seen this in the array section, so I'm not going to go deeply with them.
So I equal equal to zero to the max and through all the elements, increase the counter by one.
Otherwise, it would return to see then the DEC implementation in C will continue to make it.
And we start by in the main we will make a driver method in Maine and to test our coat.
So I want from you to put all this gold in your compiler and start your second pilot and test them and
start playing with the deck implementation and see and other data structures.
So we have added the front at the rear, the lead from military air android display and count.
And then.
We moved through four aren't equal to rear minus one cooking here, so.
Front equal to the minus one, we are internalizing them and we have a look.
As a are equal to zero.
And we start adding.
Array at this array in their five index front and index bag and seal on that front, at the rear, at
front, at the rear and at the front.
Displaying the elements in the queue will be by calling and will be executed by cleaning, display and
array, and I will delete from it is executed, remove the item and then we will display array again
and so on.
We are using the count and delete earlier and that delete.
So these are the methods how to play with the deck.
How to make it there, like a structure that you deal with, like making and adding of the frond, adding
of the rear, deleting from the front, deleting from the rear and so on.
We will see in the next video how to implement.